Finding aid to the Program of Film and Media Studies records CA.MS.01199
Smith College Archives
Program of Film and Media Studies records
1996-2019
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Film & Media Studies
CA.MS.01199
1.25 linear feet (1 record carton)
Files of the Smith College Program of Film and Media Studies, including information on the program's operation, events, and student projects.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Program of Film and Media Studies, prepared by the Office of the Provost/Dean of Faculty
Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty; Smith College. Film & Media Studies; Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty
- Film and Media Studies program files, 1996-2019; 2018-A-0077; 1.25 linear feet (1 record carton)
  - Year-end budget requests, 2002-2008; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Development of film studies, 1997-2001; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Five College Film Studies major graduation exit survey, 2008; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Student research fund requests, 2008-2011; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Presentation of the major/minor, 2000-2017; 19 folders (19 folders) (Box 1)
  - Film and Media Studies syllabi, 1997-2019; 22 folders (22 folders) (Box 1)
  - An Afternoon with Ann Hornaday, 2018-04-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Brenda Ann Kenneally Presentation, 2018-04-12; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Garrett Bradley public lecture, 2018-04-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - 6th Annual Society for Cinema and Media Studies Undergrad Conference, 2018-04-06; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FMS 290 Field Trip to The Quarters, 2018-03-27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Big Sonia Pioneer Valley Jewish Film Fesitval, 2018-03-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Pizza Gathering for FMS Majors and Minors, 2018-03-23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Kevin B Lee Video Essayist Guest Lecturer, 2018-03-19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - 5 College Film and Media Undergraduate Conference, 2018-03-03; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC Film and Video Festival, 2018-02-23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - James Portnow visit, 2018-02-19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Gaming Representation Symposium, 2017-10-27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Digital Africas Symposium at Amherst College, 2017-10-12; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Afternoon with Christine Vachon, 2017-10-12; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Robert Flaherty Film Seminar, 2017-06-17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FMS Departmental Reception, 2017-05-20; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC FMS Undergraduate Conference, 2017-03-04; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Five College Film Festival, 2017-02-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - AWOL Screening wDirector Deborah Shoval, 2016-11-15; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Black Radicallmagination, 2016-11-02; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Linda Williams Elephant of Melodrama, 2016-10-20; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Films Screening wDirector John Henry Summerour, 2016-09-26; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Screen Histories, 2016-04-11; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Rally Day Medalist Sharmeen Obaid-Chinoy, 2016-02-17; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - The Son of the Sheik Film Studies N'ton Arts Council, 2016-02-14; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Poto Mitan, 2015-10-21; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - David Weisman Kiss of the Spider Woman, 2015-04-29; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - SCMS Undergraduate Conference, 2015-04-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Filmmakers APGumbs JRWallace CANCELLED, 2015-04-13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FLS Class Lecture, 2015-02-23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FLS 282 Class Presentation Anayansi Prado and Heather Courtney, 2014-11-03; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Lisa Gossels Film Scrng and Q&A, 2014-03-31; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Five College Film Studies Undergrad Conference, 2014-03-02; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Five College Student Film and Video Festival, 2014-02-28; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Amber Bemak Local Filmmaker Speaker for FLS280, 2014-02-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Q&A wSamantha Rosen, 2013-12-05; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC Film Studies Undergraduate Conference, 2013-02-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC Student Film and Video Festival, 2013-02-22; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Graduate Study in Film Info Session, 2012-10-23; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Beth Murphy Lecture, 2012-10-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Jen Malkowski New Media and Pedagogy, 2012-04-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FLS 251 Gaming Presentation, 2012-04-19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Women Social Justice Domentary, 2012-03-31; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC Student Film & Video Festival, 2012-02-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Talk by Jonas Elrod, 2011-10-18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Graduate Study in Film Info Session, 2011-10-13; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Talk by Caetlin Benson-AIIott Paranormal Spectatorship, 2011-09-22; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Dominique Cabrera Film and Q&A, 2011-03-02; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Talk by Chris Steward Film Editor, 2010-11-18; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - AMNH Margaret Mead Traveling Film Festival Cooking History, 2010-03-30; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - African Film Festival, 2010-03-06; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Joan Braderman Film The Heretics and Q&A, 2010-02-27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Talk by Chris Holmlund, 2009-11-12; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FLS End of the Year Student Party, 2009-05-04; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Judith Helfand Serious Fun Talk and Film Screening, 2009-03-30; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - FC Student Film Festival and Award Ceremony, 2009-02-27; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Five College Student Film Festival and Award Ceremony, 2008-02-29; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Cause Collective What You See is What You Get, 2008-10-28; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Yael Bartana Trembling Time, 2008-10-22; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Wade Cynthia Alumna Filmmaker Master Class in Filmmaking Techniques, 2007-11-08; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Workshop on Media Globalism Activism, 2007-11-02; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Yau Ching Return of the Bad Girl, 2007-12-5; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Barbara Campbell Performance and New Media Artist, 2007-04-26; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Moving Images Alumane Filmmakers Bernadine Mellis & Malona Voigt, 2007-04-19; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Victoria Gamburg, 2006-02-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Mangolte Babette Filmmaker, 2005-04-05; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Marlene Reconsidered, 2004-10-15; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Marlene Reconsidered Double Feature, 2004-10-14; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Su Friedrich Talk, 2004-03-29; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Movies about Movies Film Series, 2004-03-26; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Graham Greene centenary film series, 2004-02-15; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - An Evening of Short Video Works, 2003-05-02; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Debra Zimmerman Lecture, 2003-04-21; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Melinda Barlow Lecture Feminism 101, 2003-04-14; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - New Asian American Shorts, 2003-04-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - MPC The Yes Men Igor Vamos, 2003-04-07; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Jen Meagher Lecture, 2003-04-01; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Carolee Schneeman Lecture Eros, Outrage and the Toothless Pixel, 2003-03-10; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Women in the Director's Chair Touring Festival, 2002-04-24; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)